（ジン）やはり「神の書」は　人が
手にすべきものではなかった。
The Divine Revelations is not meant for mortals.
（カイト）
まさか　神のパズルが解放されたら
こうなるっていうのか？
Are you telling me this will happen if the Divine Puzzle is released?
今　俺が見ているものが
未来だっていうのか！
Are you telling me I'm seeing the future?
お前の望んだ世界なのか…。
教えてくれ　ジン！
Is this the world you wanted?
Tell me, Jin!
ジ～ン！
Jin!
Daimon Kaito
observation logs
カイト…。
Kaito...
kimi no nounai he shinnyuu nemutteiru sukima ni
I infiltrate your brain while you're sleeping.
Baby, open the gate!
fukuzatsu sugi sekyuriti kakusareru to abakitaku naru
The security's too tough, but I want to expose what's hidden.
barabara ni chirabatteiru pasuwado wo hiroi atsume
I gather the pieces of the shattered password.
kakushin ni sematte iku sono shoutai wo misete
I get close to the core. Show me who you really are!
kantan ni kuria dekinai saki nante motto yomenai
I can't clear it easily. I can't even see what lies ahead.
kaidoku fukanou sumairu kikenna pazuru
Your indecipherable smile is a hazardous puzzle.
rokku sareta doa aru nara zutto tataite miru beki kazana hiraku wa
When you see a locked door, you should just hit it until a crack opens.
eien ni hodokenai nazo nanka wa nai
There's no mystery that lasts forever!
makiokosu, it's a supernova
I made it, it's a supernova!
tobikiri shigekitekina hirameki wo agemashou
Let's flash so bright it'd hurt!
Misskey-Misskey La-Tu-Ma
yume no naka it's a supernova
In my dreams, it's a supernova!
watashi wa sou brain diver
Yeah, I'm the brain diver!
kimi ga sagashi motometeru kotae ni nareru made
Until I can find the answer you're looking for...
Brain diver!
Shining Tears
（バロン）何か　大事なものでも
しまってあるようですね。
Looks like something important is locked in there.
（バロン）大門カイトに勝った新人ギヴァーが
いると聞いていましたが…→
I heard that there was a new Giver who defeated Daimon Kaito.
さすがですね…　ガリレオのギャモン君。
You did not fall short of my expectations, Gammon the Galileo.
（ギャモン）学園長？！
てめえ　生きてたのか！
Principal! You're alive?!
ええ…　しかし　ご覧のとおり
捕まってしまいました。
Yes. Though as you can see, I've been captured.
はぁ？！　のんきに
歩き回ってんじゃねえか？！
What?! You're walking around freely!
ふっ　歩き回ったところで
逃げ出す事など　できませんから。
Even if I'm walking around freely, I can't escape.
さっきの問題　分かった？
全然　分かんなかった。
Could you solve that last problem?
Not a chance.
Me neither... I was totally lost.
分かんなかったよね。　そうだよね。
しょうがないよね。
It was hopeless.
…ったく！　引っつくな！
Dammit! Stop following me!
（ノノハ）昨日は　どうしたのよ？！
急に　どこかへ行っちゃうし→
What got into you yesterday?
You just ran off suddenly! I was worried!
心配したんだからね！
パズルが　できねえやつには
関係ねえ！
It's got nothing to do with you if you can't solve puzzles!
で　できるもん。　私にだって…。
（知恵の輪を引きちぎる音）
I can! Just wait...
分かんないよ！　どういうこと？！
I don't get it! What's going on?
じゃあ　教えてやる。
Then let me tell you.
俺はな　「愚者のパズル」に
挑まなきゃなんねえんだ。
I have to challenge Fools' Puzzles.
お前は　足手まといなんだよ。
違う！　カイト　何か隠してる。
You're in the way.
That's not it. You're hiding something.
私には分かるんだから！
はぁ？！　何かって…　ん？！
I know it.
Huh?! Hiding?
Explain it, Kaito!
ねえ　説明してよ　カイト…。
うっ　はっ。
なんだ？　ノノハ！　どこ行った？
ノノハ！
What? Where are you, Nonoha? Nonoha!
カイト…　カイト。
Kaito! Kaito!
カイト！
はっ。
Kaito!
どうしたの？
いきなり　人の名前…。
What's wrong? Why did you start calling—
…って　ちょっ　ちょっ　ちょっ。
（生徒たち）ヒュ　ヒュー！　ヒュー！
Wh-What are you...
カ　カ　カイト！
K-Kaito!
よかった。
えっ？！　カイト…。
I'm so glad.
Kaito?
頼む…　頼むから　俺に
近づかないでくれ。
Please. Don't get close to me.
うっ？！…　カ　カイト…。
K-Kaito?
（ソウジ）待ってくれ。
ん？！
Wait.
大事な話があるんだ。
We have something important to discuss.
Long time no see, Kaito.
ひさしぶりだね　カイト。
キュービック　どういうこった？
大事な話って　何なの？
Cubic, what's going on?
What's this important thing?
あっ？！　これは？
What's that?
I continued observing Kaito.
ずっと　カイトの観察は
続けていたんだ。
観察って…　お前なぁ！
You were watching me?!
このデータは　カイトの脳における
パズル情報の処理能力を示している。
This graph shows your brain's data processing ability.
簡単に言えば　思考速度だね。
In other words, the speed you think.
思考速度？
うん。
His thinking speed?
Yeah.
この線が　理論的な人間の限界点。
This line is the theoretical limit of humans.
えっ？…　て　ことは？
Which means...
カイトの思考は　異常に加速している。
Kaito's thinking is speeding up abnormally.
人間の限界を超えるほどにね。
えっ？！
Beyond the limits of humans.
カイト　周囲の物が見えなくなったり
音が聞こえなくなるような事は→
Kaito, did you experience anything like
suddenly not being able to see or hear your surroundings?
なかった？
あっ！
あったんだね。
限界を超えて加速させるために→
You did, didn't you?
To speed up beyond your limit, your brain blocks out unnecessary information.
脳が余分な情報を
遮断しているんだ。
…で　それが　どうしたってんだ？
And what does that mean?
このままだと　思考の加速は
ありえないレベルまで→
If this keeps up, your thinking speed will reach impossibly high levels. And then...
到達してしまう。
そうなったとき…。
どうなるの？
分からない。
And then what?
I don't know.
もしかしたら　ありえないことが
起こるかもしれない。
Impossible stuff could happen. For example...
例えば…。
例えば？
For example?
いや　そんなことは
ありえないと思うけど→
No, that's impossible. I can't imagine what would happen.
でも　分からないんだ。
何が起こるか。
ただ　１つ　確かなのは…。
One thing is sure.
このまま　限界を超えた状態が
続けば…　いつかは…。
If you stay above your limit for a longer period, sooner or later, you'll...
特に　オルペウスの腕輪が発動したとき
加速は激しくなっている。
When the Armband of Orpheus is active, the acceleration is even more extreme.
カイト　もう　パズルを解くのは
やめた方がいい。
Kaito, don't solve puzzles anymore.
君が君でなくなる　その前に…。
Before you lose yourself.
大きなお世話だ。
I didn't ask for your advice.
カイト！
カイト君！
Kaito!
もう　カイト！
Come on, Kaito!
ちょっと待ってよ！　カイト！
あんな話　信じるってのか？
Wait, Kaito!
Did you believe that?
だって　最近のカイト
ホントに　おかしいじゃん！
Well yeah, because you've been so weird lately!
さっきだって…。
Just earlier too...
I solve puzzles. No matter what.
俺は　パズルを解く！
何があってもな。
どうして？　ルーク君も　ギャモン君も
無視すれば　いいじゃん！
Why? You should just ignore Rook and Gammon!
おじさんと　おばさんの敵を
討つつもり？
Do you want to avenge your parents?
ジンっていう人を助けたいの？！
ねえ　カイト！
You want to help that Jin person?
Hey, Kaito!
No one will be happy if you're unhappy!
カイトが不幸になったって
誰も喜ばない！
ノノハ。
Nonoha...
今まで　ありがとな。
はっ？！
Thanks for everything up to now.
行ってしまったね。
He left.
カイトを止めるなんて　できやしない。
No one can stop Kaito.
そんなの　初めから分かってた。
えっ？！
I knew that from the beginning.
手伝ってほしいことがあるんだ。
There's something I need your help with.
（フンガ）お待ちしておりました。
アインシュタイン…　大門カイト。
I have been waiting for you, Daimon Kaito the Einstein.
（ビショップ）
この程度の愚者のパズルが　大門カイトの
育成に有効とは思えません。
I don't think that a Fools' Puzzle of this grade would be effective in advancing Daimon Kaito.
なぜ　いまさら　このような…？
Why would you use this now?
（ルーク）確かめたいんだ。
I want to test it.
（ビショップ）逆之上ギャモンに敗北した事と
何か関係があるのですか？
Does this have something to do with the fact that he lost to Sakanoue Gammon?
（ルーク）カイトは　ファイ・ブレインへの目覚めの
最終段階に入ったのかもしれない。
Kaito might have advanced to the last level of the Phi Brain's awakening.
全てを遮断し　ただ　パズルに
向かおうとしているのかも…。
He might be blocking out everything else, only focusing on puzzles.
（ビショップ）全てを遮断？
やっと　ここまできたね。
He's blocking out everything?
We're finally here.
（バロン）おかしいとは思いませんか？
あん？
Don't you think it's weird?
Huh?
ルーク管理官のことです。
I mean Chief Rook.
これは？
ＰＯＧ総本部　中央システムの入り口。
This is...
The login screen of the POG headquarters.
ハッキングしたっていうのかい？！
そんな…　信じられない。
Are you telling me you hacked it?
I can't believe that...
Cubic, what on Earth are you doing?
キュービック君　君は一体　何を？
ルーク・盤城・クロスフィールド。　彼は　カイトを
ファイ・ブレインに育てようとしている。
Rook Banjo Crossfield is trying to raise Kaito into a Phi Brain.
ピタゴラス伯爵の命令でね。
本当に　そうなのかな？
On Count Pythagoras's orders.
I'm not so sure about that.
僕は　それ以外の何かがあるような
気がして　しかたないんだ。
I get the feeling that there's something else to it.
回想
（フンガ）そういう　たぐいまれなる
能力を持ったお方こそが→
Do you not think that a person of such amazing talent
回想
大門カイトと共にいるに
ふさわしいと思いませんか？
is more worthy to be at Daimon Kaito's side?
カイト…。
Kaito...
ルークの狙い？
Rook's goal?
本当に　全てが…　ピタゴラス伯爵の
命令なのでしょうか？
Is he really under the orders of Count Pythagoras?
私には　何かが
隠されているような気がして…。
I get the feeling that he's hiding something.
おっと！　今の俺は
ＰＯＧのギヴァさんだぜ。
Hey! I'm a Giver of the POG.
ふっ　そうでした。　しかし　随分と
思い切ったことをしましたね。
Oh, that's right.
You did something very desperate.
Yeah. I'll solve the Divine Puzzle.
ああ　神のパズルを解く。
命を落とすかもしれませんよ。
It might cost you your life.
てめえの方こそ　調子に乗って
うろついてると　ケガするぜ。
You could get hurt if you loiter around here too much.
え～っ？！
でも　ここから先に進めないんだ。
But I can't go on any further from here.
コンピューターの解析でも　答えは　これで
間違いない…　はずなのに。
Even the computer analysis shows that this is the correct answer.
キュービック君…。
お願いします。　軸川先輩！
Cubic...
Please, Jikugawa! Help me.
僕に力を貸してください！
分かってる。　先輩もＰＯＧだって。
I know that you're a member of the POG. So if they find out...
もし　ＰＯＧにバレたら…。　でも！
But...
１人で準備をしてたのかい？
Were you preparing all alone?
I'm only good at stuff like this.
僕には　こんなことしか
できないから。
カイトの過去を知って…　僕にも
力になれる事は　ないかなって…。
When we learned about Kaito's past, I wondered if there was anything that could make me stronger.
数字だけが友達だった。
パソコンや　オカベ君だけが…。
Numbers were my friends.
I thought that my computers and Okabe were all I needed.
それでいいと思ってた。
だけど…　友達になりたい…
カイトと友達になりたいんだ。
But I want to become friends... to become friends with Kaito.
そんな資格　僕には
無いかもしれないけど…。
I may not be worthy of it...
ふっ…　なんだ
気付いてなかったのかい？
You haven't realized?
君は　もう　とっくに
えっ？！
カイト君の友達だよ。
You and Kaito are already friends.
だが　僕は　ギヴァーだ。　残念ながら
パズルを解くのは　専門外…。
But I'm a Giver. Solving puzzles isn't my specialty.
そんな！
でも　実は　初めは
ソルヴァーを目指していたんだ。
But...
In the beginning, I actually wanted to become a Solver.
僕は　ＰＯＧを信じていた。
I believed in the POG.
財を…　人々の思いを…
パズルに封じて守る　尊い使命だと…。
I thought they had a noble mission of protecting treasures and people's feelings by sealing them inside puzzles.
僕も知りたいんだ。　ＰＯＧに　今
何が起きているのかを…。
I want to know what's going on at the POG now too.
Please. Don't get close to me.
回想
頼む…　頼むから
俺に近づかないでくれ。
回想
今まで　ありがとな。
Thanks for everything up to now.
カイト…。
Kaito...
この画面から
進むことができないんだ。
I can't get past this screen.
いろいろ試してみたんだけど…。
黄金比だ。
I've tried several things already.
It's the golden ratio.
えっ？！
これは　ギリシャ文字のΦ。
This is the Greek letter phi.
あっ　そうか！　Φは　黄金比を
表す記号に使われることもある！
Right! The Greek letter phi is often used for the golden ratio!
ＰＯＧのメンバーなら　全員
この数字を覚えている。
Every member of the POG knows this number.
For someone aiming to create the perfect puzzles, this number is beauty itself.
完璧なパズルを求める者にとって
Φとは　最も美しい数字→
黄金比のことなんだ。
両面？！
ええっ？！
It's two-sided?
それぞれのタイルの裏にも
図形が描かれていて→
There's an image on both sides, and it's only solved if you complete both.
どちらも完成させないと
正解にならないんだ。
そんな…　片面ずつバラバラに解いたら
永久に解けないんじゃ…。
But if we complete them separately, we'll never be able to solve it.
さすがに…　これは難しい。
This is really difficult.
両面をそろえるなんて…
すぐには計算できない。
I can't simply calculate both sides at the same time!
諦めちゃ　ダメだ。
僕たちは　２人いる。
Don't give up. We're in this together.
２人で力を合わせるんだ！
うん。
We should work together.
Yeah.
（フンガ）この建物の中に
パズルが隠されています。
There is a puzzle hidden in this building.
制限時間内に見つけだし
解いてください。
Find it and solve it before time runs out.
で　パズルの内容は？
And what's the puzzle about?
申し上げられません。
何？！
I can't tell you.
What?!
That is a rule this time as well.
それも　今回のルールです。
制限時間は　１０分。
You have ten minutes.
時間内に解けなかった場合は
後ろの粉砕機に落ちてもらいます。
If you can't solve it before time runs out,
you will fall into the shredder behind you.
And now...
では…　パズルタイム　スタート！
Puzzle time... start.
くっ　こんなかに　パズルが
隠されてるってことか！
There's a puzzle hidden in here?
イヤっ！
そうか　ルーク…　そういうことか！
I see, Rook! So that's how it is!
ここを右に動かしてみるよ。
I'll move this to the right.
Okay.
あっ。　カイトセンサーが反応してる。
The Kaito sensor is sending a warning!
カイトが　パズルを解いてるんだ。
He's solving a puzzle!
なんだって？！　止めないと！
作業を続けて！
What?! We have to stop him!
We should continue.
大丈夫。　手は打ってある。
Don't worry, I prepared for this.
ふう。　カイト君は　ファイ・ブレインとして
目覚め始めている。
Kaito is awakening as a Phi Brain.
情報を遮断し　限界を突破して
なお　加速する思考…→
He blocks out information and speeds up his thinking even further beyond his limit.
その先には　一体…。
What could be waiting for him there?
He may be able to see the future.
もしかしたら…　未来が
見えるようになるかもしれない。
未来？！
わずかな情報から　この先
起こるかもしれない事を予測し→
The future?
From minimal information, he can predict what would happen in the future, and sees it as a premonition.
それを　ビジョンとして見ることが…。
分からない…　本当に
ただの推測にすぎないけど…。
But I'm not certain. It's just a guess.
（女の子）待て～！
（男の子）待たないよ。
Wait!
No way!
待ってよ！
回想
（笑い声）
Wait!
回想
こら　カイト！
Hey, Kaito!
はい。　カイトのために
回想
作ったの。　食べて　元気出して。
Here, I made it for you.
Have some and cheer up.
まっず～！
回想
こんなもの　食えるか～！
It's horrible! How can I eat this?!
うう～　死ぬ～！
回想
ちょっと！　失礼じゃない！
Hey, that's mean!
もう～！
回想
えっ　えええ～。
（発信音）
これは？
What is...
さあ　その力を見せろ　大門カイト。
Show us your power, Daimon Kaito.
暗号だ！　音と光の
心の声
組み合わせが　文字を表している！
It's a code. The combinations of lights and sounds are the letters.
８か所のゲートに付けられた
心の声
装置が出す　音と光。
If you take the lights and sounds given by the machines at the gates,
心の声
「ド」から「シ」の
７つの音階と４色の光が→
the seven sounds of the scale from do to ti and the four colors
４行７列で　アルファベットに
心の声
対応している。
map the alphabet into a seven by four table.
答えは…　「ファイ・ブレイン」だ！
The answer is "Phi Brain"!
はぁ？！　バカな！
このスピードで　解いただと？！
Impossible!
He solved it this fast?!
おい！　誰か　いねえのか？！
おい！
Hey, is anyone there?! Hey!
カイト！　落ち着いて！
Kaito! Calm down!
It's okay, Kaito!
大丈夫だよ　カイト！
うわ～っ！
カイト！
あっ　あっ！
Kaito!
なんだ？！　なんだ？！　やめろ！
What?! What?! Stop it!
分かってる！　カイトが　私たちを
巻き込みたくないって！
I know! I know you don't want to get us involved.
１人で　何か　しようとしてるって！
でも！
あぁ！　あ～！
I know you want to do alone.
But...
私　イヤなんだ。　カイトが　悲しんだり
苦しんだりしてるの。
I don't want to let you.
I don't want to let you be sad and suffer.
カイトが元気だと　私も元気になれる。
I'm happy if you're happy.
なんでだろうね？
へへっ　おかしいよね。
I wonder why... It's weird, isn't it?
Nonoha...
私　カイトを元気にしたい…。
I want to make you happy...
カイトを元気にするから…　だから…。
I'll make you happy, so...
Please... let me be by your side.
お願い…　そばに　いさせて…。
解けた！
Solved it!
フフッ　いい手だね。
じゃあ　僕は　キャスリングと　いこう。
Nice move! I guess I should castle.
ああ　やっぱり　すごいや！
You're really good!
きょう　確かめてみたんだ。
I tested it today.
間違いない。
カイトは　もう　目覚め始めている。
Now I'm sure that Kaito is awakening.
（ジン）カイト…。
そうだよ…　ジン。
Kaito?
That's right, Jin.
もうすぐ　ここに来る。
He'll be coming here soon.
ファイ・ブレインの世界にね。
To the world of the Phi Brain.
tsukue no ue de umareta sekai
This world born on my table.
ichiban saki ni kimi ni misetakatta
I wanted you to see it first.
karappo no heya sotto nukedashite hashiri hajimeteta
I sneaked out of the empty room and started to run.
iki hazamasete oka wo noboru to
As I got to the top of the hill, out of breath,
kimi ga saki ni tsuite matteita ne
you were already there waiting for me.
takusan no hajimete kimi to mitsuketa takaramono datta
It was the first of many treasures we would find together.
kanashisa de afureta toki wa
When sorrow was overflowing in me,
nanimo iwazu ni tada soba ni ite kureta ne
you just silently stayed by my side.
ima de mo wasurenai yo
I still haven't forgotten that.
mata aou ne yakusoku wo shiyou
Let's promise we'll meet again.
kie wa shinai ano hi no sayonara
The goodbye of that day we'll never forget.
boku no subete kimi ga kureta michi
All I have I got from you,
zutto kokoro no naka hikaru yo
and it will all shine in my heart forever.